Guide to the Norman Hurd Ricker Papers, 1916-1978 MS 398
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series II: Calculations, 238002
  - Prints and negatives of diagrams, charts, graphs and calculations concerning seismic research., 238119 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Items in folder: Graphs marked, "Peaked Amplifier with non-linear phase characteristic"; Graphs marked, "Wavelet Contractor Circuit"; Notes marked, "Computation of Output Wavelet Forms; General Instructions for Procedure"; Graphs marked, "Final Completed Output Curves for making tracing"; Charts marked, "Type K Amplifier Preliminary Computations; Also Preliminary General Computations"; Charts marked, "Output disturbances from K-4 Amplifiers - Oscillograms"; Charts and graphs marked, "K Amplifier Selected final data"; Prints marked, "Response of Flat Top and K-4 Amplifiers"; Photographic negatives marked, "Response of Amplifiers to Wavelet Input"
  - Prints and negatives of diagrams, charts, graphs and calculations concerning seismic research., 238113 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Items in folder: Graphs and charts marked, "L Amplifier"; Prints marked, "Sine and Cosine Curves to be integrated in computation of Output forms. Flat Top Ampl."; Unmarked charts.; Unmarked charts.; Unmarked charts.
  - Notes entitled, Chronological record of attempts to promote activity with continuous elastic wave prospecting., n.d.; 238112 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Notes and charts entitled, Shear Wave Studies at Last Chance and Limon., 238111 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Unmarked charts., 238110 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Notes entitled, Memo: Plans for Fundamental Seismic Studies; `A Scale of Amplitudes for Use in Seismic Prospecting.', 238109 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Notebook containing typed correspondence and handwritten notes. Entitled, Trip to Dupont, Hercules, and M. 1. T.: Data on Effect of Explosives on Surrounding Media and Photography of Cracks and Waves., 238108 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Printed programs of the Third World Petroleum Congress. The Hague, 1951.; 238107 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Copy of typewritten paper entitled, The Theory of Wavelet Contraction., n.d.; 238106 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Negatives., n.d.; 238103 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Items in folder: Photographic Negatives marked, "Miscellaneous Smaller Negatives"; Photographic Negatives marked, "Small Negatives"
  - Notes and graphs marked, Early Computations; The Nature of the Shot Pulse (Development about the Shot Point.), 238102 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Series of prints entitled, Wavelet-Form Functions., n.d.; 238055 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Items in folder: Maps marked, "Fig. 1"; Maps marked, "Figs. 2-3"; Charts marked, "Figs. 4-5"; Charts marked, "Figs. 6-7-8-9"; Prints marked, "Fig. 10"; Prints marked, "Fig. 11"; Prints marked, "Fig. 12"; Prints marked, "Fig. 13"; Prints marked, "Fig. 14"; Charts marked, "Figs. 15-16"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 17-18"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 19"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 20-21"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 22"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 23"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 24"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 25-26-27-28"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 29"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 30"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 31"; Maps marked, "Figs. 32-33-34"; Charts marked, "Fig. 35"; Prints marked, "Fig. 36"; Prints marked, "Fig. 37"; Charts marked, "Figs. 38-39"; Charts marked, "Figs. 40-41"; Charts marked, "Fig. 42"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 43"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 44"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 45"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 46"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 48"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 49"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 50"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 51-52"; Maps marked, "Figs. 53-54"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 55"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 56"; Maps marked, "Figs. 57-58-59-60"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 61"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 62-63-64"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 65-66"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 67-68"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 69-70"; Graphs marked, "Figs. 71-72"; Graphs marked, "Fig. 73"
  - Series of prints entitled, Non-Relevant or Leftovers., n.d.; 238054 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Notebook containing patent for Frequency Standards Vibrating Bars, 23 June 1925.; 238053 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Typewritten paper entitled The Birth of the Paper Cone Loudspeaker., n.d.; 238052 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Reprints of published article by H. W. Fletcher entitled, Plunger Lift Makes Flowing Wells Out of Pumpers. The Oil Weekly, 29 January 1932.; 238051 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Material dealing with patents for inventions developed by Ricker., 238042 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Items in folder: Original patent documents for numbers 1934447, 1960027, 1960028, 2089983; Copies of patent documents for numbers 2921525 and 2089983; Copies of patent documents marked, "Plunger Lift," for numbers 1769637, 1844074, 1909119, 1919529, 1836877, 1815364, 1836872, 1784110, 1932479, 1836871, 1836874, 1905058, 1884245, 1836875, 1922396, 1836876, 1836873; Copies of patent documents marked, "Electromagnetic Prospecting," for numbers 1859009, 1934447, 1960027, 1960028; Folder containing copies of patent documents marked, "Seismic," for numbers 1451080 and 1599538; Copies of patent documents marked, "Seismic Prospecting," for numbers 2588291, 2351456, 2354548, 1625625; Copies of patent documents marked, "Secondary Standards of Frequency," for number 1543124; Copies of patent documents marked, "Paper Cone Loudspeaker," for number 1859892
  - Photographs showing the Mine Advisory Committee of the National Academy of Sciences, c. 1950s.; 238041 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Photographs showing the Society of Exploration Geophysicists, 1957.; 238040 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Notebook containing blueprints. Entitled, Production of Harmonics; Development of Type `G' Carrier Telephone., 22 August 1921; 238039 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Notebook containing typed memoranda and blueprints. Entitled, Large Free-Rigged Diaphogus of Double-Conical Structure for use as loud speakers., 1922.; 238038 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Small notebook containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, Undamped Periodic Elastic Waves; Early notes from old LEFAX notebook., 238037 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence regarding The Bell Telephone `Colloquium.' Includes Report on first year, 1919-20; Constitution of the Colloquium. Letter to Norman Ricker, inviting him to become a member, from the secretary, Karl K. Darrow., November 12, 1921.; 238036 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of an early model of the Portable Cathode Ray Oscilloscope., 1922.; 238035 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Chart of Western Electric Company Engineering Department., 1922.; 238034 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Letter from J. W. Horton to Ricker, 5 May 1927.; 238033 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Unidentified Machinery., 238032 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Notebook containing memoranda and notes. Entitled, Ricker vs. Hibacsko; Interference 59,575: Cone Loud Speaker Development., 1930.; 238031 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Notebook containing a published article, Ricker et. al., Frequency Measurement in Electrical Communication, as well as photographs., c.1923.; 238030 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Notebook containing handcharted graphs. Entitled, Oroginal [sic] Curves of Work on Modulations., 1919; 238029 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Notebook containing memoranda and blueprints. Entitled, Memoranda (Technical)., 1921.; 238028 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Notebook containing memoranda and blueprints. Entitled, Frequency Standards., 1921.; 238027 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Notebook containing report, photographs, and blueprints. Entitled, Frequency Measurement in Electrical Communication., 1923.; 238026 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Photographs and graphs entitled, The Plunger Lift Development (for the Hughes Tool Co.), 238025 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Notebook containing correspondence between Ricker and the Mexican Sinclair Petroleum Corporation, Jan. 1927-Dec. 1927.; 238024 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Notebook containing Torsoin Balance, Surveys., c.1920s.; 238023 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Notebook containing typed report. Entitled, Rough Draft of a Report on Development of Electromagnetic Method of Locating Buried Petroleum Deposits., Dec. 8, 1927.; 238022 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Copies of patent documents marked, Electromagnetic Prospecting, containing numbers 1803405, 1934447, 1960027, 1960028, and 1859005, 238021 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Notebook containing correspondence and graphs. Entitled, Seismic Survey, John Jackson Ranch, Chambers County, Texas; Report on First Seismic: Survey made by Humble Oil and Refining Company, 1925.; 238020 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Notebook containing reports and graphs. Entitled, Amplifier Output Forms., c.1945.; 238019 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Calendar of Research Projects., c.1920s.; 238018 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Reprints - Ricker's dissertation, and a co-authored paper, 1916-1923.; 238017 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Rough draft of a paper, The Stokes Wave Equation Has Written Into It the Interchange of Energy Between Particles., n.d.; 238016 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Five copies of typewritten paper entitled, May the Stokes Wave Equation be Universal?, n.d.; 238015 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Two copies of typewritten paper entitled, The Role of Education in This Changing World., 1966.; 238014 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Typewritten paper entitled, Stokes Wave Equation and the Propagation of a Plane Wave of Sound in a Simple Gas., 238013 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence concerning requests for reprints., c.1954-1965.; 238012 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - List entitled, Bibliographic list of published papers of Norman Ricker., n.d.; 238011 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Typewritten manuscript entitled, Composite Reflections, with photographic prints., January, 1950.; 238010 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Handwritten draft of Wavelet Propagation in Granular Media., 238009 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Many years of appointment calendars with inscriptions., 238008; (3 folders) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Small notebook containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, Wavelet Theory: Miscellaneous Formulae, and Tables., 238007 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Notebook containing memoranda, prints, and graphs. Entitled, Punch Tests, of Dupont EL 406 as Compared with Dupont Hi Vel Dynamite., 4 December 1946.; 238006 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Paper entitled, Present Developments Arising from the Wavelet Theory. Correspondence regarding reprints., 1945.; 238005 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Prints, regarding Wavelet Theory., n.d.; 238004 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Reprints of papers by Ricker. Marked, Most of these are very scarce and some are unavailable., 238003 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Series III: Wavelet Theory of Seismography, 237834
  Predominately notes, calculations, photographic negatives of figures, and text of Ricker's book.
  - Notebook containing memoranda and graphs. Entitled, EL406 vs. duPont H. V. `Punch Tests.', 238001 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Copies of report, with memoranda, prints, and graphs. Entitled, Seismic Punch Tests of E. L. 406., 1946.; 237999 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Items in folder: Graphs and memoranda marked, "Data aclative to seismic `punch' tests of duPont explosive E. L. 406 at Woodward, Okla., Nov. 5-6, 1946."
  - Notebook containing correspondence and paper. Entitled, Wavelet Contraction, Wavelet Expansion and the Control of Seismic Resolution., c.1953.; 237998 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Prints, notes, and calculations dealing with wavelet theory., 237971 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Items in folder: Photographic negatives marked, "General Wavelet Theory."; Prints marked, "Wavelet Breadth vs. Propagation Time for Shale."; Photographic negatives.; Prints marked, "Photographic Reproductions of Drawings; Old and Obsolete"; "File Index"; Graphs and calculations.; Print marked, "1939 Limon Colo.; Print of Seismogram"; Graphs marked, "Calculations"; Paper and prints marked, "Chapter 1: Historical Introduction"; Prints marked, "Chapter 2: The Nature of Seismograms"; Graphs marked, "Historical"; Graphs marked, "Complete Absorption Spectrum for a Viscous Earth"; Film negative marked, "Wavelet Theory General"; Graph marked, "Chapter 3: The Equation of Wave Propagation for an Elastic Medium with Viscous Absorption"; Film negative; Section of files entitled, "V: Wavelet Functions and Their Polynomials" Prints entitled, "Wavelet Functions"; Prints entitled, "Wavelet Functions"; Graphs and calculations marked, "Original Studies: Wavelet Functions and Wavelet Form Functions, Including Tabulation"; Charts marked, "Early Computation of Wavelet Functions"; Charts marked, "Basic Wavelet Functions"; Notebook containing plotted graphs. Entitled, "Wavelet Functions"; Chart marked "Derivation of Recurrence Formula for Wavelet Function"; Film negative marked, "Wavelet Functions all on one Sheet; Best!"; Film negatives marked, "Wavelet Functions"; Charts marked, "Wavelet Functions compiled by Betty Armstrong; There are many errors in these computations"; Typed calculations marked, "Chapter 4: Wavelet Functions and their Polynomials"
  - Prints, Notes, and calculations dealing with wavelet theory., 237935 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Items in folder: Series of files marked, "Wavelet Form Functions and the Laws of Propagation of Seismic Wavelets." Includes film negatives and charts. n.d.; Prints and negatives marked, "Obsolete."; Stencils for Wavelet forms.; Prints marked, "Chapter V: Wavelet Form Functions and the Laws of Propagation of Seismic Wavelets."; Series of files marked, "VI: Very-Near-Shot Wavelet Forms and the Nature of the Shot Pulse." Includes graphs marked, "Computation of Very-Near-Shot Forms by Graphical Integration."; Film negatives marked, "Wavelet Propagation."; Film overlays marked, "Near Shot Forms."; Film negatives marked, "Wavelet Form Functions; Step function & spike function excitation."; Prints marked, "Peak Amplitudes - Very Near Shot"; Film negatives marked, "Very-Near-Shot Wavelet Forms"; Prints marked, "Displacement form; old."; Prints marked, "Velocity form"; Charts and graph marked, "Integration of Displacement form"; Notebook containing graphs and prints. Entitled, "The Nature of the Shot-Pulse"; Prints marked, "Chapter VI: Very near shot wavelet forms and the true nature of the shot pulse."; Series of files marked, "VII: Seismic Ray Paths." Includes notes and graphs marked, "Earth with uniform velocity gradient."; Series of files marked, "VIII: Some Characteristics of Seismic Disturbances." Includes graphs and prints.; Film negatives marked, "Seismic First Motion."; Prints, graphs, and overlays marked, "Seismic First Motion."; "An original Seismogram: Minden, Louisiana."; Series of files marked, "IX: Wavelet Complexes and Seismic Resolving Power." Includes film negatives and graphs.; Prints,; Graphs marked, "Original Plotted Data; Two-Wavelet Complex"; Charts of data.; Graphs and charts marked, "The Wavelet Complex"; Graphs marked, "Synthetic Wavelet Complexes; Calculations and Curves"; Graphs marked, "Wavelet Complex Computations"; Graphs and charts marked, "Two-Wavelet complex"; Notebook containing graphs. Entitled, "The Wavelet Complex"; Notebook containing graphs. Entitled, "Gibson Zone Wavelet Complex. Katie Area, Oklahoma"; Notebook containing calculations. Entitled, "Formulae from Wavelet Theory; Appendix C"; Graphs and charts marked, "Two Wavelet Complex"; Prints.; Film negatives marked, "Wavelet Complexes"; Prints and positive film overlays marked, "Wavelet Complexes"
  - Prints, notes, and calculations dealing with wavelet theory., 237883 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Items in folder: Series of files marked, "X: Distortionless Wavelet Transmission." Includes prints and calculations.; Report marked, "Theory of Wavelet Contraction"; Prints marked, "Spectrum of Seismic Wavelet"; Prints marked, "How W. C. Characteristic Contracts Wavelet by Modifying Spectrum"; Film negatives marked, "Wavelet-Spectra"; Graph and calculations marked, "Spectrum of a Wavelet"; Prints marked, "Chapter X: Wavelet Spectrum and the Requirements for Distortionless Wavelet Transmission"; Series of files marked, "XI: The Seismograph." Includes notes.; Prints and charts marked, "Seismograph and Galvanometer"; Film negatives marked, "Seismograph and galvanometer response curves"; Graphs and computations marked, "Response of a Seismograph to Impressed Wavelet form; Harmonic Function Approach (Superceded by Wavelet Function Approach)"; Prints and graphs marked, "seismograph response curves"; Series of files marked, "XII: The Galvanometer." Includes prints and graph.; Charts marked, "Galvanometer Response to True Wavelet Input"; Film negatives marked, "Galvanometer Response, halftone"; Prints and graphs marked, "Galvanometer Response Characteristics"; Prints marked, "Oscillograms of Galvanometer Output forms for True Wavelet Inputs"; Series of files marked, "XIII: Laboratory Studies of Wavelet Contraction." Includes originals and stencils for wavelet generator.; Film negative marked, "Wavelet Contractor Circuit"; Graphs marked, "Resolution of Wavelet Complex by Wavelet Contraction"; Prints marked, "Laboratory Studies of W. C. Prints"; Notebook containing handwritten notes and prints. Entitled, "Data from Wavelet Contraction Notebook."; Charts marked, "Wavelet Contraction Frequency Allocations"; Handwritten notes marked, "Laboratory Studies of Wavelet Contraction and Seismic Resolution"; Series of files marked, "XIV: Field Studies with the Wavelet Contractor." Includes prints and notes marked, "Comparison of Wavelet Contractor Seismogram with Conventional Seismogram. El Reno, Okla."; Print marked, "Experimental Time Delays; W. C. Amplifiers"; Charts marked, "Wavelet Breadth"; Prints marked, "Resolution Wavelet Complex; Switch Positions 24 to 17"; Prints marked, "Delay Time Wavelet Contractor"; Charts marked, "Wavelet Contractor Type E Time delay Observations"; Prints marked, "Calculated Out Forms for Wavelet Input of Arbitrary W. C. Characteristics"; Print marked, "Allocation of Frequencies to W. C. Switch Positions"; Prints marked, "Ground Roll Suppression - Contraction Ratio"; Notes, both typed and handwritten, marked, "Wavelet Contractor Operating Truck and Equipment; Specifications and Ideas"; Typed notes related to "Wavelet Contractor Conference: Sept. 30, 1947"; Film negatives marked, "Wavelet Contractor"; Prints marked, "Original W. C. Oscillograms from which slides were made"; Charts marked, "Contours drawn on transition frequency"; Series of files marked, "XV: Experimental Studies of the Primary Seismic Disturbance." Includes notes and graphs marked, "Amplitude vs. Charge Size"; Charts marked, "Breadth Squared and Transition - Frequency Contours in Section Limon and Last Chance, Colo."; Charts marked, "Original Data"; Charts marked, "Wave Surface; Limon and Last Chance, Colo."; Prints marked, "Wavelet Spectra - Comparison Observed with Ideal; Limon, Colo."; Prints marked, "All Primary Forms; Last Chance, Colo."; Charts marked, "Primary Forms; Limon, Colo."; Charts marked, "Variation of Form; Limon, Colo."; Prints marked, "Photos of Specimen Seismograms; Limon, Colo."; Prints marked, "Seismic First Motion"; Film negative marked, "Nine Primary Forms at Limon, Colo."; Film negatives marked, "Wavelet-Breadth vs. Travel Time; Refinery Residue Wax."; Drawings on tracing cloth marked, "Seismic Punch vs. Shot Depth; Limon and Last Chance, Colo."
  - Notebook containing reprints and handwritten calculations. Entitled, Wavelet Theory Formulae., c.1960.; 237882 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Notebook containing reprint of Harold Jeffreys', Damping in Bodily Seismic Waves., 1931.; 237881 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Series marked, Smaller Negatives. Concerning wavelet theory., n.d.; 237865 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Items in folder: "IV: Wavelet Functions and their Polynomials"; "V: Wavelet Form Functions"; "VI: Very Near Shot Wavelet Forms; Nature of the Shot Pulse"; "II: The Nature of Seismograms"; "VIII: Some Characteristics of Seismic Disturbances"; "IX: Wavelet Complexes and Seismic Resolving Power"; "X: Distortion Wavelet Transmission"; "XI: The Seismograph"; "XII: The Galvanometer"; "XIII: Laboratory Studies of Wavelet Contraction"; "XIV: Field Studies with the Wavelet Contractor"; "XIV: Figures Used in Book"; "XV: Experimental Studies of the Primary Seismic Disturbance"; "XVI: Shooting in Sand"; "XXI: Nature of Internal Friction"
  - Pages marked, Sheets from Notebook on Wavelet Function, 237864 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Graphs marked, Miscellaneous, 237863 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten notes marked, Wavelet Theory; General Programme, 237862 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Handwritten notes marked, Misc. Papers, 237861 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Collection of script fonts., 237860 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Memoranda and paper entitled, The Form of the Seismic Disturbance due to an Explosion. Delivered before the 281st meeting of The American Physical Society, held at The Rice Institute - Houston, Texas, Nov. 28-29, 1947., 237859 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Typewritten paper entitled, The form and Laws of Propagation of Seismic Wavelets. Marked, 12th Copy., 237858 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Letters of Introduction marked, Round-the-World Trip, 237857 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence marked Professor Hajime Narumi and Y. Takesada; Kyoto; Hiroshima; Tokyo., 1964-1976.; 237856 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Bound notebook containing a handwritten list. Entitled, Bibliography., 29 July 1946.; 237855 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Notebooks containing Wavelet Theory., 237850 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Items in folder: Notebook containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, "Symbols used in Wavelet Theory"; Notebook containing handwritten calculations and graphs. Entitled, "Wavelet Theory Applied to Black Body Radiation"; Notebook containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, "The Possible Connection between the Wavelet Theory of Seismogram Structure and Wave Mechanics"; Notebook containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, "Formulae and Symbols"
  - Notebook containing reprints, handwritten calculations, and graphs. Entitled, Wavelet Forms (Spherical Wave Surfaces)., 237849 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Notebook containing prints of graphs. Entitled, Geophone Response to Wavelets., 1946.; 237848 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Two notebooks entitled, Galvanometer Response, n.d.; 237845 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    items in folder: Containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, "Theoretical"; Containing prints of graphs. Entitled, "Experimental"
  - Prints of graphs and charts, entitled, End of Chapter XV., 237844 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous prints, n.d.; 237843 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Two notebooks containing notes on wavelet theory., n.d.; 237840 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Items in folder: Containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, "Formulae Wavelet Theory"; Containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, "Wavelet Functions Formulae"
  - Notebook containing prints and handwritten calculations. Entitled, Theoretical and Experimental Seismograph Research., 237839 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Typewritten paper, graphs, and calculations. Marked, Spoiled Work in Xerox Copying, 237838 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - "First 12 Chapters of Seismic Wavelets, Xerox Copy.", n.d.; 237837 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Notebook containing handwritten calculations. Entitled, Notes on the Attenuation of Sound Waves through Rayleigh Scattering., 237836 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Notebook containing a handwritten bibliography. Entitled, Absorption and Scattering., 237835 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Series IV: Artifacts and Ephemera, 237821
  Containing the bound copy of Vol. 1 of The Autobiography of Norman Hurd Ricker, several photograph albums, boxes of glass slides, and scientific equipment.
  Note that one item in box 24 and all items in box 25 were deaccessioned in August 2009. The remaining items in box 24 were incorporated into box 23.
  - Two artifacts, 237831 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Items in folder: Headphones; Unidentified machinery
  - Bound copy of Vol. 1 of "The Autobiography of Norman Hurd Ricker." Marked as Ricker's personal copy., 237830 (Box 23, Folder 1)